Hello.
In this next section, we're going to set up an enemy character to get started briefly close on our
engine and attach somewhere in this course.
I'm going to make sure to include this content file.
Just select it and drag it somewhere inside of your Unreal Engine project with all the images selected,
just right click and go spread actions and apply paper to detect your settings.
The next thing we're going to do is set up the animations that our enemy is going to have just to keep
things organized.
I'm going to create a folder for each of its separate animations.
So once you've done that, just drag the respective animation into its photo.
Let's head into the first order.
The attack one.
Then if we just right click on this image, I go extractions and go extract Sprite.
This is kind of different to how we extracted our characters, right?
So our characters came with all the images individually.
This sprite came with all the images together.
In Unreal Engine, there are two ways we can extract sprites.
So the first way is to use this auto method, and here Unreal Engine will try to get each frame for
Sprite and try to extract it.
Although you can see it's kind of struggling with this last one.
So it may not be best to do auto, but sometimes it can work.
The other method we have is grid, and here we can specify how we'd like it to trip up our image.
So here, under cell width, I know that if I have a value of 150, then it's going to split all the
images accurately.
But I could change this to be something like 100 and it would split up all the images in that way.
I'm just going to change it back and go extract.
And then I'm gonna collect all the sprite right click and go create flipbook, and I'll call this skeleton
attack.
So we're not going to do the same thing with our skeletons, other animations.
So we go to the death folder.
Right click on it goes fractions, sprites, go to grid and change this to be 150.
They're all going to be 150 in the cell width and just go extract our select all the sprites, create
a flipbook and call the skeleton death.
And what this death one just like the last one right click and go create flipbook and call the skeleton
dead body because later when we kill Stanton will make it play the scam to death.
And then we just want a flipbook of the Stanton's dead body.
Next we head over to the other powder.
We will extract the sprite.
Go to grid, put 150 here and extract.
So hopefully you've got the hang of this.
I'm just going to fast forward and do this for the other sprites.
So once you created a flipbook animation for all of your Stanton's animations just to be organized,
I'm going to create a new folder and call it flip books.
And I'm just going to put all these folders inside of it.
Hello.
The next thing I want to do is set up my skeleton's animation blueprint.
So I'm going to right click and create a new folder.
And just pull this animations.
Then if we head inside here, just right, click again and go ahead and select animation source and
just call this a skeleton animation source.
If we head inside here, I want you to go add new and set new animation sequence and just cool this
first one skeleton item.
Then add another one and just call this skeleton walking.
But now we're just going to work with these two animations.
So here, understand an idol.
I'm going to slap my skeleton.
I do animation and hair under skins and walking.
I'm going to set my skin to walking animation.
Once you've done this, you can just go save.
Next.
Before we set up our sentence animation blueprint, we're going to set up a very simple script and blueprint.
So I'm going to go back to my Scantron folder and just right click and go new folder and call this blueprint.
Then we head inside here on the right Click and Go Blueprint class and under all classes, look for
Paper Z.
And this one paper Z character.
Select it and just call the Scantron underscore beep.
We don't need to do anything else because inside my animation blueprint, we're going to reference this
phantom beep so we can just access some variables inside of that.
Next, we can just right click and go.
Paper z, seq, Paper Z Animation Blueprint.
And we want to set the scan to an animation source.
So a reference to scan animations.
I'll just go to my skeleton and beep.
Then if we head inside here.
I bet on it.
We're going to play a reference to our skeleton so we can access an.
They went on.
And we're going to create a reference to our skeleton blueprint just so that we can access any variables
inside of our Scranton character.
So event on end, I'm going to right click and will get owning actor.
And from here we're going to drag off and forecast to Scranton.
As a skeleton.
We'll use this animation blueprint.
Then we just want to right click on this variable and print it to a variable.
Then we head into our animation graph.
We just want to right click and go new state machine and hook us up here.
And we head inside our state machine.
If we just check out an animation state, just call this idle slash walk.
And we head inside here.
We're going to check to see the velocity of our Stanton.
If it's not equal to zero.
Then we'll play our walking animation.
If it is equal to zero, then we'll play our other animation.
So our struggle here and look for good velocity.
Well, travel panic will break to three F and we'll see if the philosophy and the x axis is not equal
to zero.
Then, depending on the value of this, we'll play an animation.
So we'll look for blend.
There's one slight animations by Paul.
If this is true, then we will play our stance of voting.
If this is false, then we'll play Oscar into an idol.
So I'm going to take this one up here and go compile and save.
Nice.
Next, we're going to be ready to set up our scan and beep.
So I'll scan to walk and move around our level.